So now that we have this, we have this other thing called emits.
And so to kind of basically provide a quick overview for those
who might not have used it in view three,
if you remember inside of your code,
whenever you wanted to emit an event within view,
you would actually use dollar sign emit.
So let's say this click handler right here,
you say emit, and then some sort of event.
So let's be like test event.
And so where am I on the restaurant card?
So if we go over to our app,
and go to our restaurant, yep,
we'll see here in something, okay, we're good.
So if we go inside of the view dev tools,
and then we pull this up a little bit,
wait, restaurant card, yes, okay, yeah, I'm in the right place.
And then let's go to timeline.
You'll see that when I click delete,
it's actually showing me here that,
here it is, here's the custom event.
Here you go, it's fired off this event called test event.
And so this is actually for those who haven't used it before,
this follows basically basic job-ship conventions, right?
Because you have an event that's triggered somewhere,
it bubbles up, and then you want to do something with it.
So that's how currently we're working with our cards right now,
is that it's emitting an event like delete restaurant,
for example, and then the parent who has the data
would then go ahead and perform the necessary tasks to do that.
So the thing is, especially in view two,
this was actually all that you basically did.
And what happened was components got a little bit complex,
because you had this emitting events here and there,
is kind of hard to track.
And so in view three, we introduce an option,
similar to props, where you can define the kind of events
that the component is emitting.
And so typically what we saw before is that it's just the fine
as an array with the list of the names of the events.
But with the compiler macro and TypeScript,
I do think it gets a lot cleaner.
So we have here, as we can say, defined emits,
and then inside of defined emits, it can take an array,
it can take an array just like this,
or rather than having just an array like this,
I'm going to comment this out so that we have this for comparison.
We're actually going to give our events a tight,
and this is actually super helpful, particularly with events.
Because what we end up getting is the ability to say,
okay, so we have an event that comes in,
and we can say it's just a generic event,
but you could also be a specific, you could be like,
oh, this is a keyboard event.
And that keyboard event can then,
we'll do more of the event handles later,
but this is pretty nice.
So for now, we know that this event is going to be called
Delete Restaurant, just a double check,
yep, so you have your E here,
you pass in the name of the event that's going to happen.
And then after that, you're going to pass in whatever payload
that it's expecting,
and then whether or not it's supposed to return anything,
and it's typically not, so it's void.
So in that particular case, we have E here,
we know that it's going to have a payload,
and the payload is going to be,
two, should be restaurant,
so we'll type that, just like this.
Okay, there we go.
So what's nice about this now,
is that when we want to actually use this, right?
Because before all you could do is define the name of it,
so now when we call the emits,
something pretty cool happens.
When we emit the thing,
if I hit command space and hit up,
you actually notice that it actually lists the event names
that we've defined in the autocomplete.
So even though it's a string and not like a constant,
it actually knows that, hey,
I actually should look for the string,
and so not only can I do that,
then I can even say, okay,
well, if I did like one, two, three, for example,
it'll say, hey, by the way,
this particular event is looking for a restaurant.
And this is pretty big because as we know,
events can be really clunky to manage in JavaScript,
especially because there's different types,
and we expect it to do different things at different times.
So being able to type your event and be very specific about
what kind of thing we're expecting, that's huge.
So now all we gotta do then,
is basically we want the props dot restaurant.
And that's it.
And so once with all that autocomplete,
you get that because you're typing your events,
which, again, is something in my opinion you want to be doing,
because when you don't do something like this,
and myths get really, really tricky to track,
and much less trying to figure out what they do.
You know, almost seems like every time you have
the debug event that's being admitted,
you have to start over from figuring out like the stack trace of why,
it's a certain way.
Whereas here, we are being so explicit that a delete restaurant event
will take a payload that is of type restaurant.
That's it.
And that, I think, does wonders for us when it comes to,
you know, actually scaling our code.
So now that we've come to the end of that,
does anyone have any questions about what we just covered?
Yes.
Why don't we have to import to find a myths and to find props?
That is a great question.
So one of the things that, I feel like the JavaScript community
kind of goes back and forth a little bit on this with,
is that they try to ship away any global imports
that you might need just to make it one
less thing that you have to import.
And because view knows,
for a fact that your scripts set up,
these are kind of the compiler macros that I was talking about,
where there are optimization done in advance.
However, there really is nothing stopping you from saying
to find props to find myths,
because I can totally see the value in being explicit.
And it's not going to yell at you.
But on the other hand, if you're one of those people that want to
ship away as much as humanly possible,
that is there for you.
But I will go ahead and leave this here for records,
record, keeping say.
And then actually I'll just fuse these together.
There we go.